Guide to the Yale Tocqueville Manuscripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- AMERICAN TRIP, APRIL 1831--APRIL 1832; B.
  - Letters and Reports, 1
    - B.I.a.1. Tocqueville Letters Home, 1831-1832 ("published") (Box 4)
      These were in the hand of Gustave de Beaumont and were taken by White from the manuscript of volume 7 of Beaumont's Oeuvres Completes d'A. de Tocqueville. White took only those eighteen which he did not find in original or in copy in the Redier manuscripts, see below B.I.a.2. For an estimate of Beaumont's considerable omissions and alterations, consult White catalogue 1W below, E.IV.e. Beaumont's copies are still in the Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, T:IV.A.1. Bonnel copied all but the first page of one letter (later corrected) from what White apparently labelled "Paquet 15". As for what may have happened to the originals, see Jardin comments in E.VI.
      -juin 1831, Sing Sing, to father (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet "15", T:IV.A.1)
      -9 juin 1831, New-York, to Vtesse (Emilie?) (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet "15", T:IV.A.1)
      -17 juillet 1831, Auburn, to Mother (Bound copy sep. folder. 1931)
      -3 aout 1831, Detroit, to Lesueur (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1)
      -14 aout 1831, (Buffalo), to father (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1)
      -21 aout 1831, sur le lac Ontario, to mother (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1)
      -7 septembre 1831, Albany, to Lesueur (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1)
      -27 sept. 1831, Boston, to mother (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1)
      *-10 8bre 1831, New-York, to Earnest de Blosseville (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1)
      *-10 octobre 1831, New-York, to Comtesse de Grancey (ALS now in her family's archives.) (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1)
      -22 8bre 1831, Philadelphie, to Charles Stoffels (Corrected by GWP from Stoffels d'Hautefort copy) (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1)
      -24 8bre 1831, Philadelphie, to mother (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1) See fragments of original manuscript in B.I.a.2. For other letters published by Beaumont (with changes) in O.C. VII, see B.I.a.2. (B.I.a 1-2 on MS Vault Microfilms 536)
      -29 (9?) 8bre 1831, New York [?], to Bouchitte (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1.)
      -25-30 9bre 1831, a bord du Fourth of July, to Vicomte de Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "151", T:IV.A.1.)
      -6 Xbre 1831, Louisville, to mother (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1.)
      -20 Xbre 1831, Memphis, to father (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1.)
      -25 Xbre (1831), sur le Mississip[p]i, to mother (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1.)
      -24 janvier 1832, Washington, to father (Bonnel copy from Beaumont copy, Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, Paquet no. "15", T:IV.A.1.)
    - B.I.a.2. Tocqueville's Letters Home, 1831-1832 (largely "unpublished" before GWP book) (Box 4)
      These are the letters which White found with Redier and set aside to be copied by Doysie's copyists as Dossier 3.I (see White catalogue 3W) Jardin states (1963): "Ces copies, faites pour la plupart par Redier, correspondent-elles a des originaux egares? Dans l'etat actuel de mon information, voici ce que je pense:
      - les manuscrits des lettres a ses parents et a ses freres n'ont pas et‚ retrouves
      - par contre des lettres a des cousins (Mme de Leusse) ou des amis (Ernest de Chabrol) existent chez leurs heritiers ou les acquereurs de ces bibliotheques."
      -26 avril 1831, a bord du Havre, to mother (Published by Beaumont with changes) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS.; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -8 mai 1831, a bord du Havre, to father (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -14 mai 1831, New-York, to father (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -18 mai 1831, New-York, to Ernest de Chabrol ("Pub. by R"? Yes) (Redier Copy) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -28 mai 1831, New-York, to Bd. and Alexandrine (White copied part) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -28 mai 1831, New-York, to Lesueur (Published by Beaumont with changes) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -9 juin 1832 ("mai") 1831, New-York, to Ernest de Chabrol (Redier Copy) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -19 juin 1831, New-York, to mother (plus Newspaper article) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -20 juin 1831, New-York, to Edouard de Tocqueville (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -20 juin 1831, New-York, to Ernest de Chabrol (copy "Published by R"? No) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -20 juin 1831, New-York, to Alexandrine (Published by Beaumont with changes) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -28 juin ("juillet") 1831, New-York, to Eugene Stoffels (copy with changes) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -29 juin 1831, New-York, to Louis de Kergorlay (copy verified- Redier with changes) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -30 juin 1831, New-York, to Lesueur (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -"Suite de la lettre du 30 juin, supprime comme faisant double emploi avec celle a Mme de Grancey sur Atala" (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -4 juillet 1831, Albany, to father (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -16 juillet 1831, Auburn, to Ernest de Chabrol (copy, partially published by Redier [R?]) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -"25 juillet 1831" Batavia, to Alexandrine (Published by Beaumont with changes) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -17 aout 1831, Buffalo, to Ernest de Chabrol (Redier copy) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -(aout 1831)?, to Dalmany [?] (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -7 7bre 1831, Albany, to Vicomtesse Hippolyte de Tocqueville (2 copies) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -10 7bre 1831, Boston, to Edouard de Tocqueville (Published by Beaumont with changes) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -17 septembre 1831, Boston, to Ernest de Chabrol (Redier copy) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -7 8bre 1831, "Harfort", to father (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -7 octobre 1831, Hartford, to Ernest de Chabrol (Redier copy) (trans. by White) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -10 8bre 1831, New York, to Mme de Grancey (fragment) (Beaumont changes) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -10 8bre 1831, New York, to B... (almost certainly Blosseville?) (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -18 octobre 1831, Philadelphie, to Ernest de Chabrol (copy "pub. R"? No) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -18 8bre 1831, Philadelphie, to Mme Edouard (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -18 8bre 1831, Philadelphie, to Eugene Stoffels (Published by Beaumont with changes) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -24 octobre 1831, Philadelphie, to mother (Published by Beaumont with changes) (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -26 octobre 1831, Philadelphie, to Ernest de Chabrol (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -8 5bre 1831, Philadelphie, to M. [Felix Le Peletier d'Aunay?] (draft with corrections) (belongs in B.I.c.) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -8 9bre 1831, Philadelphie, to Louis de Kergorlay (fragment) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -19 novembre 1831, Philadelphie, to Ernest de Chabrol (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -26 novembre 1831, a bord du "4th July" sur l'Ohio, to Ernest de Chabrol (Redier copy) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -28 9bre 1831, sur l'Ohio, (to sister-in-law) (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -1er decembre 1831, (Cincinnati), to Ernest de Chabrol (Redier copy) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -4 Xbre 1831, Cincinnati [to Hippolyte?] (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -6 decembre 1831, Louisville, to Ernest de Chabrol (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -27 Xbre 1831, "sur le Mississippi", to Ernest de Chabrol (fragment) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -16 janvier 1832, de la baie de Chesapeak, to Ernest de Chabrol (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -16 janvier (1832), Dans la baie de Chesapeak, to Mme Edouard de Tocqueville (Beaumont changes) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -20 janvier 1832, Washington, to Edouard de Tocqueville [or Ernest de Chabrol?] (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -24 janvier 1832, Washington, to Edouard de Tocqueville (Redier copy) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -9 fevrier 1832, New-York, to Edouard de Tocqueville (Redier copy) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      -4 avril 1832, Paris, to Gustave de Beaumont (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1; Original given to GWP by Mme de Larminat. See below, C.I.a.2.)
      -22 avril 1832, St. Germain, to Eugene Stoffels (copy, published by Beaumont) (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier III.1)
      Still Missing:
      -8 Nov. 1831, Tocqueville to Ernest de Chabrol (copy seen by White?)
      -25 Dec. 1831, Tocqueville, Tocqueville to Carne (copy seen by White?)
    - B.I.b.1. Lettres de Gustave parti du Havre le 2 avril 1831. (Box 5)
      Bound letterbook of copies. Originally found and copied by GWP at Beaumont-la-Chartre. Presented to GWP by Mme de Larminat and so to Yale in 1955. For list of these letters see below under B.I.b.2. GWP originally supposed that the copybook was the in hand either of Gustave or more probably of his brother Jules. Jardin (1963) identifies the copyist as Gustave himself.
      These letters have been copied, annotated and published as:
      Gustave de Beaumont: Lettres d'Amerique, Texte etabli et annote par A. Jardin et G. W. Pierson (Publications de la Sorbonne: Serie "Documents"--22, Presses Universitaires de France, 1973)
      General note
      Bound volume
    - B.I.b.2. Beaumont Letters Home, 1831-1832 (Box 5)
      Typed copies of the letters in the above letterbook made by GWP at Beaumont-la-Chartre in 1930. Two of these letters subsequently corrected by GWP from originals loaned by Mme de Langavant who also allowed the copying of an additional fragment.
      -25 avril 1831, a bord du vaisseau Le Havre, a mon pere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -8 mai 1831, a bord du Havre, a ma mere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -16 mai 1831, New-York, a mon pere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -26 mai 1831, New-York, a Jules (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -7 juin 1831, New-York, a ma mere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -18 juin 1831, New-York, a Achille (corrected by GWP from Langavant original) (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -29 juin 1831, New-York, a mon pere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -4 juillet 1831, Albany, a Jules (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -14 juillet 1831, a Eugenie (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -22 juillet 1831, Canandagua, a ma mere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -24 juillet 1831, a bord de l'Ohio sur le lac Erie, a Ernest de Chabrol (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -1er aout 1831, Detroit, a mon pere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -2 aout 1831, a bord du Superieur sur le lac huron, a Ernest de Chabrol (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -11 aout 1831, a bord du Superieur, lac Michigan, a Achille (corrected by GWP from Langavant original) (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -21 aout 1831, Lac Ontario, a bord du vaisseau "the Great Britain," a mon pere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -5 7bre 1831, Albany, a mon pere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -16 7bre 1831, Boston, a Jules (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -25 7bre 1831, Boston, a Achille (fragment) (GWP copy from Langavant original)
      -7 octobre 1831, "Har[t]ford" (Connecticut), a ma mere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -16 8bre 1831, Philadelphie, a mon pere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -26 8bre 1831, Philadelphie, a Felicie (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -8 9bre 1831, Philadelphie, a Achille (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -8 novembre (1831), Philadelphie, a Clemence (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -17 novembre (1831), Philadelphie, a mon pere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -1er decembre 1831, Cincinnati, a Eugenie (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -4 decembre 1831, (sur l'Ohio), a Jules (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -15 decembre 1831, Sandy Bridge, a ma mere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -25 decembre 1831, (a bord du bateau a vapeur Louisville, sur le Mississippi), a Achille (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -16 janvier 1832, Norfolk, a mon pere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
      -20-22-23 janvier 1832, Washington, a ma mere (GWP copy from Beaumont-la-Chartre letterbook)
    - B.I.c. Correspondence and Relations with Americans, 1831-32: - (Letters, diaries, essays, etc.) (Box 6)
      (Twenty-eight of the original letters were acquired from Mme de Larminat in 1955)
      -5 nov. 1830, Paris, W. C. Rives to Vicomte de Beaumont (Original from Larminat)
      -22 fevrier 1831, Avallon, B. [Randot?--Jardin] to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      - [mars 1831] Ch. Lucas to Tocqueville with letters of introduction. (not now on hand) (Original from Larminat: noted also by GWP)
      -25 mars 1831, Paris, Hyde de Neuville to William Short (GWP copy from LC)
      -28 (mars) 1831, Paris, Beaumont a D.B. Warden (GWP copy from LC)
      -15 mai 1831, Phila., D'Annery a Tocqueville et Beaumont (Original from Larminat: noted also by GWP from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -16 May 1831, (N.Y.), "J.O.M." [James O. Morse] to Tocqueville et Beaumont (Original from Larminat: noted also by GWP from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -17 mai 1831, Wash., Serurier a Tocqueville et Beaumont (Original from Larminat: noted also by GWP from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -18 may 1831, Sing Sing, George W. Cartsright via St. Andre (Original from Larminat: noted also by GWP from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -20 May 1831, N.Y., William W. Campbell to ? (Original from Larminat: noted also by GWP from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -21 May 1831, (N.Y.), John R. Livingston Jr. to ? (Original from Larminat: noted also by GWP from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -22 May 1831, (N.Y.), J. W. Smith to ? (Original from Larminat: noted also by GWP from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -24 May 1331, New York, William W. Campbell to ? (Original from Larminat: noted also by GWP from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -24 mai 1831, N.Y., Tocqueville a William Short (GWP copy from LC)
      -26 May 1831, Phila., William Short diary note (GWP copy from LC)
      -18 June 1831, N.Y., Tocqueville to J. W. Francis (Original by purchase)
      -20 June 1831, N.Y., H. D. Sedgewick to sister (Original from Larminat: noted also by GWP from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -23 June (1831), (N.Y.), Ph. Hone diary note (GWP copy from NYHS)
      -28 June 1831, Tocqueville to Dr. Francis (Original by purchase)
      -4 Aug. 1831, Auburn prison, Rev. B.C. Smith to Beaumont (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -18 Aug. -11 Sept. 1831, Detroit, Detroit, Courier, 3 letters (Photocopy from LC: See B.V.b.)
      -24 Aug. 1831, Montreal, Mondelet to Neilson (Photocopy from Pub. Arch. C.: See B.V.c.)
      -12 7bre 1831, Boston, Beaumont and Tocqueville to Rev. Barrett (GWP copy from Hawkins: HSP: Gratz)
      -[Sept. 1831, Boston] Joseph Coolidge Jr. to Jared Sparks (GWP copy from H: Sparks)
      -18 Sept. 1831, Franz Lieber to family (GWP copy from Robson Hunt. See B.V.a. and C.I.d.)
      -21 Sept. 1831, Boston, Dr. Lieber to Tocqueville and Beaumont (Original from Larminat. See C.I.d. GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -25 Sept. 1831, Boston, Ellen W. Coolidge to Mother (GWP copy from HJC manuscripts)
      -27 Sept. 1831, Boston, (F.C.) Gray to Beaumont (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -28 Sept. 1831, (Boston), Edward Everett diary note (GWP copy from MHS: Everett)
      -30 Sept. 1831, Boston, Joseph Coolidge Jr. to N. P. Trist. (GWP copy from LC: Trist)
      -30 Sept. 1831 (Boston), William Sullivan to ? (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -1 Oct. 1831, (Boston), Edward Everett diary note (GWP copy MHS: Everett)
      -1 Oct. 1831, (Boston), J. Tuckerman to ? (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -1 Oct. 1831, (Boston), Questions by Tocqueville to Jared Sparks (GWP copy from H: Sparks)
      -10 Oct. 1831, Phila., P.S.A.M.P.P. resolutions (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -18 Oct. 1831, (Phila.), Roberts Vaux to Beaumont and Tocqueville (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -1 Oct. 1831, Phila., H. D. Gilpin to Edward Livingston (GWP copy from HSP: Gilpin)
      -29 Oct. 1831, Boston, Jared Sparks to N. Diles (GWP copy from H: Sparks)
      -9 9bre 1831, Phila., Beaumont to Prof. Jules Ducatel of Baltimore (Original: GWP purchase)
      -8 11 mo. 1831, Phila., Roberts Vaux to Governor Wolf (GWP copy from ESP: Wolf)
      -19 Nov. 1831, Phila., Beaumont a Joseph Coolidge, Jr. (Doysie copy from Redier MSS see White Cat. 1W: Dossier I.16)
      -19 Nov. 1831, Phila., Form letter, 45 plus questions [missing?] (Original from Larminat [?] GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -20 Nov. 1831, Phila., Samuel R. Wood to Beaumont and Tocqueville (Original from Larminat: [?] GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -20 Nov. 1831, (Phila.), Roberts Vaux to Beaumont and Tocqueville (Original from Larminat: [?] GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -2 Dec. 1831, Cincinnati, Tocqueville to Jared Sparks (GWP corrections on Adams ed. from H: Sparks)
      -Tocqueville to Jared Sparks, more questions (Doysie copy from R. brouillon)
      -27 Dec. 1831, Trenton, Samuel L. Southard to ? (Doysie copy from Redier MSS see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I.24)
      -[Dec. 1831? Cincinnati?], S.P. Chase to Gustave de Beaumont and Tocqueville (Larminat)
      -5 Jan. 1832, Boston, Joseph Coolidge, Jr. to N.P. Trist (GWP copy from LC: Trist)
      -9 Jan. 1832, N.Y., R. Riker to ? (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -11 Jan. 1832, Boston, Jared Sparks to Tocqueville (Original [missing?] from Larminat: Doysie copy from Redier MSS see White Cat. 3W: Dossier II.33g2) (GWP noted corrections from H.)
      -20 Jan. 1832, Boston, Sparks Journal (Original [missing?] from Larminat: Doysie copy from Redier MSS see White Cat. 3W: Dossier II.33g2) (GWP noted corrections from H.)
      -20 Jan. 1832, ("1830"), Wash., Tocqueville to Jared Sparks (GWP copy from H: Sparks)
      -21 Jan. 1832, Washington, Serurier a Edward Everett (GWP copy from MHS: Everett)
      -21 Jan. 1832, (Wash.), Edward Everett diary note (GWP copy from MHS: Everett)
      -22 Jan. 1832, (Wash.), Edward Everett diary note (GWP copy from MHS: Everett)
      -24 Jan. 1832, Phila., B.W. Richards to ? (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier II. 33g7)
      -27 Jan. 1832, (Pittsburgh), John Patterson to Beaumont and Tocqueville (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -28 Jan. 1832, (Wash.), Edward Everett diary note (GWP copy from MHS: Everett)
      -2[?] Jan. 1832, (Wash.), Edward Everett diary note (GWP copy from MHS: Everett)
      -30 Jan. 1832, Baltimore, R. W. Gill to (missing) [?] (Doysie copy from Redier MSS White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 24)
      -31 Jan. 1832, Boston, Jared Sparks to Tocqueville (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier II. 33g3)
      -2 Feb. 1832, Boston, Jared Sparks to Tocqueville (Doysie copy from Redier mss,; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier II. 33g4) (GWP noted H. corrections)
      -2 Feb. 1832, (Boston), Jared Sparks Essay on Town Govt... (GWP noted H. corrections)
      -2 fev. 1832, (Wash.), Beaumont a Trist (GWP copy from LC: Trist)
      -2 Feb. 1832, Phila., B.W. Richards to Beaumont (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier II. 33g6)
      -3 Feb. 1832, Phila., B.W. Richards to Tocqueville and Beaumont (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 33g5)
      -4 Feb. 1832, Boston, Jared Sparks to Tocqueville (GWP copy from H: Sparks: Also Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -6 Feb. 1832, (Phila.), Roberts Vaux to Beaumont and Tocqueville (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -7 Feb. 1832, Phila., Joseph McIlvaine to Beaumont and Tocqueville (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 24)
      -7 Feb. 1832, Phila., H.D. Gilpin to Edward Livingston (GWP copy from HSP: Gilpin)
      -8 Feb. 1832, Phila., Joseph McIlvaine to ? (Original from Larminat: GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -8 Feb. 1832, Phila., Joseph McIlvaine to Beaumont (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier II. 33g9)
      -8 Feb. 1832, Phila., Joseph McIlvaine to Beaumont and Tocqueville (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier II. 33glO)
      -11 Feb. 1832, Baltimore, R.W. Gill to Beaumont and Tocqueville (Doysie copy from Redier MSS; see White Cat. 3W: Dossier I. 24)
      -14 Feb. 1832, Boston, Francis Lieber to Tocqueville or Beaumont (Original from Larminat: See C.I.d. GWP noted from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -15 Feb. 1832, Boston, Joseph Coolidge Jr. to N.P. Trist (GWP copy from LC: Trist)
      -16 Feb. (1832), (New York), Ph. Hone diary note (GWP copy from NYHS: Hone)
      -16 Feb. (1832), (N.Y.), Jared Sparks diary note (GWP copy from H: Sparks)
      -16 Feb. 1832, (N.Y.), Gustave de Beaumont to N.P. Trist (GWP copy from LC: Trist)